It's a long way from L.A. to Denver Long time to hang in the sky
从洛杉矶到丹佛的路很远，悬挂在天空的时间很长
It's a long way home to starboard in the sky
回家的路也很长，横亘在天空中
Sweet Rocky Mountain Paradise Oh, my sweet Rocky Mountain Paradise
甜蜜的落基山天堂 哦，我甜蜜的落基山天堂
Springtime is rolling out slowly The gray skies are bringing me down
春天慢慢来临，灰色的天空让我心情低落
I can't remember when I've ever been so lonely I forgot what it's like to be home
我不记得自己何时如此孤独，我忘记了家的感觉
I can't remember when it's like to be home I think of my lady's sweet memories
我不记得家的感觉，我想起了我女士甜美的回忆
I think of the children's sweet smiles I think of my home and starboard and last night
我想起孩子们甜蜜的笑容，我想起我的家、星板和昨晚
All my friends and the snow covered hills All my friends are the snow covered hills
所有的朋友和白雪覆盖的山丘，所有的朋友都在白雪覆盖的山丘
Can I tell you I'm happy to be here To share in this time
我能告诉你我很高兴能在这里，在这段时间分享吗
Oh, I see here the shows of changes And the feeling of new friends to find
哦，我在这里看到了变化的迹象，还有寻找新朋友的感觉
And I see here some new friends to find It's a long way from this place to Denver's hills
我在这里看到了一些新朋友要找寻，从这里到丹佛的山丘路途遥远
Long time to hang in the sky It's a long way home to starboard in the sky
悬挂在天空的时间很长，回家的路也很遥远，横亘在天空中
Sweet Rocky Mountain Paradise Oh, my sweet Rocky Mountain Paradise
甜蜜的落基山天堂 哦，我甜蜜的落基山天堂
Hello folks and welcome once again to the Rocky Mountains in my little hometown of Aspen, Colorado
大家好，再次欢迎来到科罗拉多州阿斯彭小镇的落基山脉
One of the most beautiful spots in all the world
世界上最美丽的地方之一
Now Aspen's known mainly for skiing but it has an entirely different side
现在阿斯彭主要以滑雪闻名，但它还有一个完全不同的一面
And that's the time of the year when music starts to echo through these mountains
那是一年中音乐开始在这些山间回荡的时候
And the Aspen Music Festival brings together some of the finest musicians in all the world
阿斯彭音乐节汇聚了世界上一些最优秀的音乐家
Add that to all the things that you can do here when the snow is gone
加上在雪消融后你可以在这里做的所有事情
And you have a pretty good idea of what our show is all about
你就对我们的节目有了相当清楚的了解
My guests tonight are Itzhak Perlman, James Galway, my very special guest star is Miss Beverly Sills
今晚我的特别嘉宾有伊扎克·佩尔曼，詹姆斯·加尔韦，还有非常特别的嘉宾贝弗利·希尔斯女士
And I've got her riding a horse if you can believe that
她骑着马，如果你能相信的话
I've also got her singing some pretty nice songs
我还让她唱了一些非常好听的歌曲
Stick around folks, it's a wonderful show
请大家继续关注，这是一场精彩的演出
Thank you very much
非常感谢
Thank you so much
She called me right up when she arrived, asked me one more time to come
她一到就打电话给我，又一次邀请我过去
But living on an LA freeway, it's my kind of having fun
但是生活在洛杉矶的高速公路上，也是我的一种乐趣
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the range
我想我更愿意待在我的牧场
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
Than lay me down in love at Lady's chain
而不是躺在女士的枷锁下沉沦于爱情
We were just beginning
我们才刚刚开始
There's such an easy way
有一种轻松的方式
Laying back up in the mountains
靠在山上
Making love for sunny days
享受阳光明媚的日子
She got tired of picking daisies
她采下一朵雏菊
And cooking my meals for me
又去为我做美味的点心
She can live the life she wants to, it's all right with me
她可以过她想要的生活，对我来说没问题
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the range
我想我更愿意待在我的牧场
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
Than lay me down in love at Lady's chain
而不是躺在女士的枷锁下沉沦于爱情
I'd rather live on the side of the mountain
我宁愿生活在山的一边
Than wander through many of the concrete steams
也不愿漫游在许多混凝土河流中
I'd rather laugh with the rain and the sun shine
我宁愿在雨水和阳光下放声大笑
And lay down my sundown in some starry field
惬意地躺下，看黄昏夕阳西下，看夜晚星罗棋布
But I miss her when I wake alone
但当我独自醒来时，我想念她
The absence of her laughter is a cold and empty sound
她的笑声不再，只剩冰冷和空洞的风声
Her memory always makes me smile
和她一起的记忆总能让我微笑
And I want you to know
我想让你知道
I love her, yes I love her
我爱她，是的我爱她
Just enough to let her go
以至于让她离开
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the range
我想我更愿意待在我的牧场
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
Than lay me down in love at Lady's chain
而不是躺在女士的枷锁下沉沦于爱情
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
I think I'd rather ride the range
我想我更愿意待在我的牧场
I think I'd rather be a cowboy
我想我更愿意成为一个牛仔
Than lay me down in love at Lady's chain
而不是躺在女士的枷锁下沉沦于爱情
Lee Holbridge, ladies and gentlemen!
李·霍尔布里奇，女士们先生们！
Miss Beverly Sills, definitely one of a kind
贝弗利·希尔斯女士，绝对独一无二
Opera star, and yes, cowgirl?
歌剧明星，是的，还是牛仔？
I really enjoy introducing the mountains to people
我非常喜欢向人们介绍这些山
I wouldn't have missed it for anything
我不会错过这个机会的
I'm sorry about the rain, here's a little sprinkle going on
很抱歉有点下雨了，有点小雨滴
There's very little snow
雪很少
Following one of the most dazzling singing careers in the history of opera
在歌剧历史上最耀眼的演唱生涯之后
Beverly Sills has moved on to become
贝弗利·希尔斯已经转而成为
General Director of the New York City Opera Company
纽约城市歌剧公司的总监
And it's easy to see why she's one of the most beloved personalities in her field
很容易看出她为什么是她领域中最受喜爱的人之一
Right up above the ridge here, Beverly
就在这个山脊上，贝弗利
You know, it's like a chunk of my youth
你知道，这就像是我年轻时的一部分
Because when I was a little girl I used to do jigsaw puzzles
因为当我还是个小女孩的时候，我经常做拼图游戏
With mountain scenes just like this
就像这种山景一样的场景
So how you doing? You all right?
你好吗？你还好吗？
Oh, yeah!
噢，是的！
All right
好的
You know, I've heard of horse operas, but this is ridiculous
你知道，我听说过马戏，但这太荒谬了
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la
My special guest star, Miss Beverly Sills, Rocky Mountain style
我的特别嘉宾明星，贝弗利·希尔斯女士，洛矶山风格
Let the bright, scary feeling flow
让明亮、可怕的感觉流淌
There's a lot uplifting in your toughest flow
你最艰难的时刻里有很多振奋人心的东西
Let the bright, scary feeling flow
让明亮、可怕的感觉流淌
There's a lot uplifting in your toughest flow
你最艰难的时刻里有很多振奋人心的东西
Let the bright, scary feeling flow
让明亮、可怕的感觉流淌
In burning matter and in love
在燃烧的物质中和在爱中
There's a lot uplifting in your toughest flow
在你最艰难的时刻里有很多振奋人心的东西
Did you ever see a color like this?
你见过这样的颜色吗？
You know, it's a lot like New England with the color change
你知道，这很像新英格兰的颜色变化
It's really my favorite time of the year in Colorado
这真的是我在科罗拉多最喜欢的时节
Yeah, it's the fall
是的，是秋天
We'll be back with more of Beverly Sills
我们会带来更多贝弗利·希尔斯的内容
Plus James Galway and Itzhak Perlman
还有詹姆斯·高威和伊扎克·珀尔曼
Don't go away
别走开
Whoa!
哇！
You alright?
你没事吧？
Hiya, Rick!
嗨，瑞克！
That either look terrifying or great?
那是看起来可怕还是棒极了？
Great!
棒极了！
Have a good day!
祝你今天过得愉快！
Can you imagine a more beautiful setting for a music school?
你能想象一个更美丽的音乐学校场景吗？
You know, back in the 1800s, this place used to be a silver mine
你知道吗，在19世纪，这个地方曾经是一座银矿
But these days it's home to about 900 students
但如今这里是大约900名学生的家园
who each summer come here to learn from the musical masters
他们每个夏天都来这里向音乐大师学习
and to gather inspiration from the mountains, the forests, the rivers, the birds, the animals, and each other
并从山川、森林、河流、鸟类、动物和彼此中汲取灵感
Doesn't take too long to find out that it's working either
很快就会发现这也很有效
Just listen
听着
Every year around the middle of June, the students and teachers begin arriving in Aspen from all over the world
每年六月中旬左右，来自世界各地的学生和老师开始抵达阿斯彭
Before long, the town is alive with over 900 young musicians settling in for summer classes
不久之后，这座城镇就会充满着900多名年轻音乐家，准备开始暑期课程
Getting acquainted with the town may come first, but making music is what the festival and school are all about
先熟悉这座城市，但音乐创作才是音乐节和学校的核心
The standards are high, and as things get into full swing, the town and surrounding mountains become filled with the sounds of arpeggios and scales
标准很高，随着事情进入全面开展阶段，城镇和周围的山脉充满了琶音和音阶的声音
Nobody wastes a moment preparing themselves for a rigorous audition by music director, George Mester
没有人会浪费一刻准备迎接音乐总监乔治·梅斯特严格的试音
It all began over 30 years ago with a special celebration attended by Albert Schweitzer and Arthur Rubinstein, both musicians themselves
一切始于30多年前的一次特别庆祝活动，阿尔伯特·施韦泽和亚瑟·鲁宾斯坦都参加了，他们都是音乐家
The idea of centering a music festival in Aspen grew slowly into what it is today
将音乐节设在阿斯彭的想法逐渐演变成了今天的模样
With the raising of the tent and arrival of over 150 pianos and other instruments, the Aspen Music Festival and School are declared officially open
随着帐篷的搭建和150多台钢琴和其他乐器的到来，阿斯彭音乐节和学校正式开幕
Before the summer is out, over 80,000 international visitors will attend the concerts hosted by board chairman Edgar Stern and President Gordon Hardy
在夏天结束之前，将有超过8万名国际游客参加由董事会主席埃德加·斯特恩和总裁戈登·哈迪主持的音乐会
This is the break of a rehearsal this morning at the Aspen Music Tent for a concert that's going on this afternoon
这是今天早上在阿斯彭音乐帐篷里为今天下午音乐会排练的间歇
featuring the most famous and by far the most popular flutist in the world, Mr. James Galway
由世界上最著名也是最受欢迎的长笛演奏家詹姆斯·加尔韦演奏
Mr. Galway recorded one of my songs on an album a little over a year ago
加尔韦先生在一年多前的一张专辑上录制了我的一首歌曲
The song was Annie's song and he is consented this morning to our doing that together
那首歌是《安妮的歌》，今天早上他同意我们一起演奏
And I am thrilled to death by that and also nervous
我为此感到非常激动，同时也很紧张
I don't believe it
我简直不敢相信
Are you ready to do it?
你准备好了吗？
Sure
当然
Alright
好的
The man with the magical flute
那位拥有神奇长笛的男士
You fill up my senses
你充满了我的感官
Like a night in a forest
像是森林中的夜晚
Like the mountains in springtime
像春天的群山
Like a walk in the rain
像在雨中漫步
Like a storm in the desert
像沙漠中的风暴
Like a sleepy blue ocean
像一片安静的蓝色海洋
You fill up my senses
你充满了我的感官
Come fill me again
再次来填满我
Sing with us
和我们一起唱
You fill up my senses
你充满了我的感官
Like a night in a forest
像森林中的夜晚
Like the mountains in springtime
像春天的山脉
Like a walk in the rain
像雨中的漫步
Like a storm in the desert
像沙漠中的风暴
Like a sleepy blue ocean
像宁静的蓝色海洋
You fill up my senses
你充满了我的感官
Come fill me again
再次来填满我
Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy, that's wonderful
哦，天啊，天啊，天啊，太棒了
Thank you
谢谢你
And now I'm very proud to introduce to you the one and only Mr. Itzhak Perlman
现在我非常荣幸向你介绍唯一无二的伊扎克·佩尔曼先生
Mr. Itzhak Perlman
伊扎克·佩尔曼先生
Itzhak, you know I really find it hard to believe that I've got you out here fishing.
伊扎克，你知道我真的很难相信我把你带来这里钓鱼了。
You know it would be really great if we catch a fish.
你知道，如果我们能钓到一条鱼，那就太棒了。
Mr. Itzhak Perlman
伊扎克·佩尔曼先生
Hey, I got something.
嘿，我钓到了点什么。
Wait a minute. I think I got him.
等一下。我觉得我钓到了。
Wait, come on.
等等，快点。
All right.
好的。
Yay!
耶！
All right, it's a rainbow.
好的，这是一条彩虹鱼。
It's a life-long and long forgotten fish.
这是一条一生中被遗忘的鱼。
Oh, that's a big fish.
哦，那是一条大鱼。
Gorgeous.
真漂亮。
Oh my goodness.
哦，天啊。
Well, I better throw him back in the water.
嗯，我最好把它扔回水里。
Give him a chance.
给它一个机会。
Mr. Itzhak Perlman
伊扎克·佩尔曼先生
Don't go away, folks. We'll be right back with Beverly Sills and Itzhak Perlman.
不要走开，朋友们。我们马上回来，与贝弗利·希尔斯和伊扎克·佩尔曼一同。
Oh, what a beautiful day it is.
哦，多么美好的一天。
Take my hand and say you'll follow me.
牵我的手，说你会跟随我。
It's long been on my mind.
这在我心里很久了。
You know it's been a long, long time.
你知道，已经很久很久了。
I'll try to find the way that I can make you understand
我会尽力找到让你理解的方法
the way I feel about you
我对你的感受
and just how much I need you
以及我是多么需要你
to be there where I can talk to you
在那里我可以和你交谈
when there's no one else around.
当周围没有其他人的时候。
Follow me where I go, what I do and who I know.
跟随我去任何地方，做任何事情，认识任何人。
Make it part of you to be a part of me.
让它成为你的一部分，成为我一部分。
Follow me up and down, all the way and all around.
跟随我上下左右，一路上走来，四处游荡。
Take my hand and say you'll follow me.
牵我的手，说你会跟随我。
You know I'd like to share my life with you
你知道我想与你分享我的生活
to show you things I've seen,
向你展示我看过的事物
places where I'm going to and places where I've been.
我即将去的地方和曾经去过的地方
To have you there beside me and never be alone.
让你在我身边，永远不会孤独
And all the time that you're with me is when we'll be at home.
只要你和我在一起的时候，我们就在家。
Follow me where I go, what I do and who I know.
跟随我去任何地方，做任何事情，认识任何人。
Make it part of you to be a part of me.
让它成为你的一部分，成为我一部分。
Follow me up and down, all the way.
跟随我上下，一路走。
Take my hand and say you'll follow me.
牵我的手，说你会跟随我。
Bluegrass has always been a popular form of music,
蓝草音乐一直是一种受欢迎的音乐形式，
but I'll bet you've never heard it played
但我敢打赌你从未听过它以
with a 110-piece orchestra.
110人管弦乐团的演奏。
For the sailor's gone, the room is bare,
船员已经离开，房间空空如也，
the old piano's sittin' there
老钢琴就坐在那儿，
with someone's hat left hangin' on the rack.
架子上还挂着某人的帽子。
Empty chairs are wooden floor that feels a touch of shoes no more
空椅子，木地板，不再感受到鞋子的触感，
waitin' for the dancers to come back.
等待着舞者们的回归。
And the fiddle's in the closet of some daughter of the town.
小提琴放在镇上某位女儿的衣柜里。
The strings are broken, the bow is gone,
琴弦断了，琴弓不见了，
and the cover is buttoned down.
盖子扣紧了。
Sometimes on December nights when the air is cold
有时在十二月的夜晚，当空气很冷
and the wind is right, there's a melody
当风刚刚好，会响起一段旋律
that passes through this town.
在这个小镇上飘荡。
Playing with the Aspen Festival Orchestra is a real treat,
与阿斯彭音乐节交响乐团一起演奏是一种真正的享受，
but it took the fabulous Itzhak Perlman
但是需要了不可思议的伊扎克·佩尔曼
to give us a taste of down-home fiddle
来为我们带来家乡小提琴的风味
the way only he can play it.
只有他才能演奏出这样的味道。
Go for it!
加油！
One, two, three, four.
一，二，三，四。
and the fiddle
小提琴
Man Video
男人视频
Oh yeah!
哦耶！
Aspen has long been known for its creative atmosphere,
阿斯彭长久以来以其富有创造力的氛围而闻名，
and through the years it has stimulated a wide variety of artistic expression.
多年来激发了各种各样的艺术表现形式。
Not many people think of bodily combat as an art form,
很少有人将肉体战斗视为一种艺术形式，
but Thomas Crumb, president of the Aspen Academy of Martial Arts,
但阿斯彭武术学院院长托马斯·克拉姆
demonstrates the dance-like art of an ancient oriental discipline known as Aikido.
展示了一种被称为合气道的古老东方学科中类似舞蹈的艺术。
Aikido is the art of harmony, a way of life which integrates physical and spiritual growth
合气道是和谐的艺术，一种将身心结合的生活方式
through the coordination of the mind and the body.
通过协调思维和身体。
Aspen may be a long way from the Orient,
阿斯彭也许离东方很远，
but I'm sure the ancient masters would approve of this beautiful setting as a home for their teachings.
但我相信古代大师们会认同这个美丽的环境作为他们教诲的家园。
Whale bones and crosses stand against the Arctic sky.
鲸鱼的骨头和十字架耸立在北极的天空中。
Wind blows through the graveyard where our fallen fathers lie.
风穿过我们陨落的先辈长眠的墓地。
Eternal snow that covers them, the shadows of the sun.
永恒的雪覆盖着他们，阳光的影子。
The mighty struggle on the seas, a way of life is run.
海上的伟大奋斗，一种生活方式在进行着。
I'll sing for you, my father, for the ancient sacred ways.
我会为你唱歌，我的父亲，为了古老的神圣之路。
How the hunter loved the hunter, how the night becomes the day.
猎人是如何爱猎人，夜晚是如何变成白昼的。
Aikido is the art of harmony, a way of life which integrates physical and spiritual growth
合气道是和谐的艺术，一种将身心结合的生活方式
through the coordination of the mind and the body.
通过协调思维和身体。
Aspen may be a long way from the Orient,
阿斯彭也许离东方很远，
but I'm sure the ancient masters would approve of this beautiful setting as a home for their teachings.
但我相信古代大师们会认同这个美丽的环境作为他们教诲的家园。
Whale bones and crosses stand against the Arctic sky.
鲸鱼的骨头和十字架耸立在北极的天空中。
Wind blows through the graveyard where our fallen fathers lie.
风穿过我们陨落的先辈长眠的墓地。
Eternal snow that covers them, the shadows of the sun.
永恒的雪覆盖着他们，阳光的影子。
The mighty struggle on the seas, a way of life is run.
海上的伟大奋斗，一种生活方式在进行着。
I'll sing for you, my father, for the ancient sacred ways.
我会为你唱歌，我的父亲，为了古老的神圣之路。
How the hunter loved the hunter, how the night becomes the day.
猎人是如何爱猎人，夜晚是如何变成白昼的。
The circle of the mighty spirit keeps us in its fold.
强大精神的圆环将我们团结在一起。
The warmth of understanding, like a light shot through the cold.
理解之温暖，如同寒冷中的一束光。
Then bring to me my people, touch them with your loving hand.
带给我我的人民，用你慈爱的手触摸他们。
Lead them from confusion, lead them back unto the land.
引领他们远离困惑，领他们回到大地之中。
For sickness seems to block their path, it clouds my people's eyes.
因为疾病似乎堵塞了他们的道路，使我的人民眼中迷茫。
The promise that an idle truth will reap a golden light.
空泛真理的承诺将带来金色的光芒。
Whale bones and crosses stand against the Arctic sky.
鲸骨和十字架矗立在北极的天空中。
The wind blows through the graveyard where our fallen fathers lie.
风吹过我们陨落的先辈长眠之地。
The timeless hunt, the journey back to what we once came from.
永恒的追寻，回到我们曾经来自的地方。
The mighty struggle on the seas, a way of life is run.
海上的巨大奋斗，一种生活方式在进行着。
There's nothing to do, so Annie and I get out and enjoy all the town has to offer.
无事可做，所以安妮和我外出，享受小镇所提供的一切。
Like an impromptu performance by the Aspen String Trio.
就像阿斯彭弦乐三重奏的即兴表演。
Or challenging the champs in a local softball game.
或者挑战当地垒球比赛的冠军。
When the big kids are through, the little kids take over.
大孩子们结束后，小孩子们接手了。
Everyone takes advantage of the warm weather while they can.
每个人都尽可能地利用暖和的天气。
Especially in a town as sports minded as Aspen.
尤其是在阿斯彭这样一个热衷于体育的小镇。
To the kids, this ballet class is just a lot of fun.
对孩子们来说，这个芭蕾舞班只是一场很有趣的活动。
But to us parents, it's a great way to interest them in the art of movement and self expression.
但对我们父母来说，这是激发他们对运动艺术和自我表达的兴趣的好方法。
It takes years to perfect the graceful movements of dance.
要完美掌握舞蹈的优雅动作需要多年时间。
But from the dreams of little girls, future ballerinas are born.
但从小女孩的梦想中，未来的芭蕾舞演员诞生了。
Because he called for us brother.
因为他称呼我们为兄弟。
Because he called the earth his mother.
因为他称地球为他的母亲。
They drove him out into the rain.
他们把他赶到雨中。
Some people even said the boy from the country wasn't safe.
一些人甚至说乡下的男孩不安全。
Because he spoke to fish in the creek.
因为他与溪流中的鱼交谈。
He tried to tell us that the animals can speak.
他试图告诉我们动物也会说话。
Who knows? Perhaps they do. I know they do.
谁知道呢？也许他们能。我知道它们能。
How do you know they don't? Just because they've never spoken to you.
你怎么知道它们不能？只是因为它们从未和你说话。
The boy from the country left his home when he was young.
乡下男孩年幼时离开了家乡。
The boy from the country, he loves the sun.
乡下男孩，他热爱太阳。
He tried to tell us we should love the land.
他试图告诉我们应该热爱这片土地。
We just turned our heads and laughed.
我们只是扭头笑了笑。
See, we did not understand.
你瞧，我们不理解。
Sometimes I think the boy from the country is the only one who sees.
有时我觉得乡下的男孩是唯一看得到的人。
The boy from the country doesn't want to see the forest through the trees.
乡下的男孩并不想被树挡住了看到森林。
The boy from the country is the only one who sees.
乡下的男孩是唯一看得到的人。
The boy from the country doesn't want to see the forest through the trees.
乡下的男孩并不想被树挡住了看到森林。